Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives, 1982-2001 MSS.231
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXIII: Pride and Progress / The Right Stuff, 1985-1990
  - 1986
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 49 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 12/2/1986], December 1986; ID: 231.0715 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0715)
      6. Washington, DC, coverage of politics and clips of openly gay politicians discussing the gay and lesbian political agenda
      7. Seattle, Washington, 3 of 5 TV stations refuse to air AIDS awareness announcement
      8. Study finds that 3/4ths of the people with CMV strain of AIDS show improvement after treatment with the experimental drug DHPG
      9. Congress refuses to overturn Washington D.C.'s AIDS insurance law prohibiting providers from testing for AIDS infection prior to insurance approval
      10. Sports Report, with clips from film, "American Anthem"
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, with clips from "LA Law" about an AIDS victim, and interview with culinary writer Sara Friedman, on wild mushrooms
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Oh, Coward!" Broadway revue
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 50 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: unknown], circa 1985 - 1986; ID: 231.0716 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0716)
      1. NEW FORMAT: Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Joyce Hunter, and Darrell Yates Rist
      2. US State Dept requires employees to take HIV antibody test, disallowing those positive from working abroad
      3. Vermont put $150,000 to educate state about AIDS, NYC Board of Education produces a public school film "Sex, Drugs, and AIDS"
      4. Kentucky state county judge ruled that Sodomy Laws violate the Kentucky state constitution
      5.Discussion of a National Gay and Lesbian March on Washington DC, Oct 11th 1987
      6. Discussion of the New York Times' playing down the threat of AIDS infection for heterosexual couples, and misrepresentation of the statistical facts of infection
      7. Andy Humm on Cary Grant's lawsuit against Chevy Chase
      8. Continuing coverage of the 2nd annual meeting of gay and lesbian elected officials in Washington, DC
      9. National Association of Gay and Lesbian Democratic Clubs to remain part of the party despite 53% voting to remove Democratic affiliation
      10. Mood of the gay and lesbian leaders, and need for a national leader like Harvey Milk
      11. Gay politicians agree to back the March in Washington DC
      12. News Brief, announcements
      13. Belle Glade, Florida, study finds high rate of AIDS infections due to sexual contact and IV drug use
      14. Georgia Fraternal Order of Police Officers tries to ban homosexuals from joining the force
      15. Gay man forced to resign from Canadian Mounted Police sues the department
      16. Man banned from seeing his child due to positive HTLVIII test appeals the court's decision
      17. Announcement of film "Rights and Reactions"
      18. Sports Report, with clips from the 1986 Gay Games
      19. Closing credits over news clips of tennis star Boris Becker
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, with clips from "Escape from Alcatraz"
      3. Announcement of Cary Grant's death and homosexual rumors, with clips
      4. Richard Pryor's Barbara Walters' special on question of AIDS status, with clips
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 51 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 12/11/1986], December 1986; ID: 231.0717 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0717)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Joyce Hunter, Darrell Yates Rist, and Tom Stoddard
      2. Catholic bishop forbids AIDS Project Los Angeles from holding seminars in Catholic buildings due to the project's endorsement of condom use
      3. National Gay Rights Advocates win $3 million settlement for San Francisco homosexuals who were denied employment or promotion by Pacific Bell
      4. Discussion of the New York Board of Education's AIDS awareness film, "Sex, Drug, and AIDS"
      5. Discussion of bathhouses and the possible reopening of NYC's largest, St Mark's Bathhouse
      6. Discussion of the State Department's requirement for HTLVIII testing for applicants and employees
      7. Andy Humm on refusing to cooperate with AIDS-discriminatory job practices
      8. World Health Organization finds AIDS rates may soar in Latin America and Asia
      9. Justice Sandra Day O'Connor finds that the Supreme Court's decision on the Georgia sodomy case may be altered by further prosecution and hearings
      10. Austin, Texas, proposal for banning the discrimination on the basis of sexual preference generally supported
      11. Alabama, Birmingham News requires job applicants to take HIV test and bans those positive from jobs
      12. Jackson, Mississippi, State bans language of sexual equality from Constitution, opting for ban on "gender" discrimination only
      13. San Francisco, National Gay Rights Advocates issue complaint against Health America's rejection of all San Francisco applicants in order to avoid AIDS-positive applicants
      1. Announcement, 1986 Sydney Gay Mardi Gras program preview party, with clips
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of The High Heeled Women's "It's A Broad, Broad, Broad World," with clips
      3. "Just Ask Raz" advice segment
      COMMERCIAL: The World of Video
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 52 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 12/22/1986], December 1986; ID: 231.0718 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0718)
      2. Discussion of particular problems homosexuals face during the holiday season, including coming out to parents, bringing partner to holiday dinner, coping with intolerant family
      3. AIDS transmission outside the bloodstream, and ability to infect tissue, and the New York Times' continuing bias of male anal sex as primary method of infection
      4. State's Constitutional rights in light of the Bowers v Hardwick sodomy case decision
      5. Discussion of "gifts" each guest has received this year, including the strengthening of the gay community in the national spotlight
      6. Andy Humm on enlightening the ignorant through vocal support for gay rights
      7. Hotline for latest treatments for AIDS and experimental treatments
      8. Federal government's AIDS hotline becomes privatized, is expanding to 24 hours, moving to NYC
      9. Lee University in Pennsylvania grants official status to a gay, lesbian, and bisexual student group
      10. 62 new AIDS education PSAs used to educate average TV viewer, starring an assortment of Hollywood celebrities
      11. Lesbian woman ends legal fight over her dismissal from the ROTC in 1982
      12. Newly adopted Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 continues to include language that can be used to ban gay people from entering the country
      13. Philadelphia, police commissioner appoints a liaison to the gay community and commits to fully investigating complaints of anti-gay violence and hate
      14. Sports Report, with clips of Greg Louganis performing a circus act
      1. This Week in History with Jeff Bixby
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of off-Broadway musical, "Have I Got a Girl for You!"
      3. Michael Weyand interviews Walter Williams about his study of homosexuality in Native American culture, "The Spirit and the Flesh"
      4. Reminder from Razor Sharp to contact those friends who do not have families
      5. $100.000 gained in an art auction to benefit five AIDS organizations in San Francisco
  - 1987
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 1 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 12/31/1986], circa 1986 - 1987; ID: 231.0719 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0719)
      Special Episode "1986 in Review," with GCN clips and coverage from the year
      1. Gay and Lesbian Alliance Against Defamation protests outside the New York Post offices
      2. Coverage of the National Gay and Lesbian Taskforce meeting, featuring interviews with Sara Throne, Virginia Apuzzo, Peter Fowler, Urvashi Vaid on the impact and continuing future of the gay service organization
      3. Mayor Koch attacked at the Proclamation of 1987 Gay Pride Week
      4. Andy Humm on the 17th anniversary of the Stonewall Riots
      5. Raymond Jacobs on the psychological impact of AIDS on communities
      6. Gay Friends and Neighbors in Brooklyn
      7. Coverage of the 17th Annual Gay and Lesbian Pride Day Parade in New York, 29 June 1986
      8. Raymond Jacobs on dealing with AIDS related deaths in the young gay community
      9. Clips from the July 4th 1986 NYC protest against the Supreme Court passage of the "Sodomy Laws"
      10. Interview with Michael Hardwick, of the Bowers v. Hardwick Georgia "Sodomy Laws" case, and discussion of the case
      11. Lyndon LaRouche placing the "AIDS quarantine" initiative on the California ballot
      COMMERCIAL: Dr. Ruth taping, call for gay guests to attend
      12. "Stamp Out AIDS" project, interview with John Glines
      13. Gay Christopher St Festival Committee sponsors a candlelight vigil for AIDS Resources Center Inc, which cares for homeless persons with AIDS
      14. Gina Alvarez discusses the increase of activism of young gay students, especially on college campuses
      15. Human Rights Campaign Fund Dinner, with speeches by Coretta Scott King and Harvey Fierstein
      16. Closing credits, over clips of the Village Halloween Parade
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 2 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 1/6/1987], January 1987; ID: 231.0720 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0720)
      1. Gay Week in Review, special "looking ahead" discussion, with Andy Humm, Joyce Hunter, and Darrell Yates Rist
      2. Expecting AIDS statistics continuing to rise, especially among heterosexual couples
      3. Expected AIDS funding, or lack there of, from the Reagan administration
      4. Possible cures and vaccines for AIDS
      5. Condom ads on network television?
      6. Closeted or out attitudes of gay persons in 1987
      7. Funding for lesbian and gay services
      8. Progression or overturning of sodomy laws
      9. March on Washington DC
      10. Guests answer questions, "If you could change one thing for gay people this year, what would it be?" and "Do you think Ronald Reagan is going to be in office at the end of this year?"
      COMMERCIAL: "Gay Year in Review" VHS tape
      11. Andy Humm on letter-writing to politicians
      12. San Francisco organization, Mobilization Against AIDS, plans to launch a national boycott of Delta Airlines for its gay rights violations
      13. Committee of Interns and Residents votes to refuse to hold conventions in states with sodomy laws
      14. Amsterdam, plan to build monument to memory of homosexuals killed by the Nazis in World War II
      15. Georgia, in first ruling since passage of sodomy laws, two men were fined and given community service for committing sodomy
      16. Sacramento, council members tried to overturn the city's gay rights bill
      17. Boston, Beth Israel Hospital employee fired for not working with AIDS patients, attempts to get unemployment benefits
      18. Sports Report, interview with Ron Keel of the Manhattan Community Athletic Association about getting gay persons involved in activities
      19. Closing credits
      1. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, Stephen Holden's NY Times review of comedy act Barb Nelson's negative stereotypes
      2. Interview with playwright Robert Patrick of "Blue is for Boys," and actors Allan Gassman and David Gallagher
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Pageant" the satirical drag show-themed musical
      4. Interview with a furrier from New York's Zamir Furs about maintenance and type of fur coats for men
      5. Christmas message from GCN San Francisco to GCN New York
      6. And Another Thing... with Brett Siereveld on having pride as a gay person
      COMMERCIAL: Zamir furs
      7. Closing credits over coverage of a bowling event
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 3 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 1/12/1987], January 1987; ID: 231.0721 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0721)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Joyce Hunter, Darrell Yates Rist, and Evan Wolfson
      2. AIDS and the right to privacy, with special reference to public figures
      3. The media's ignoring gay-related news stories in their year-in-review issues, gay visibility
      4. Gay survivors of AIDS deaths, legal victories, and marriage rights
      COMMERCIAL: GCN's "Year in Review"
      5. Andy Humm on Reagan's lack of AIDS funding in 1987 budget
      6. New law forbids the Military from using HIV testing program for "adverse actions" against gay service members
      7. Denver, St John Episcopal Cathedral opens a housing complex exclusively for people with AIDS
      8. Tennessee, Tri-Cities AIDS project conduct awareness education
      9. San Francisco man successfully challenges his insurance company to gain health benefits
      10. Minnesota, governor issues executive order banning discrimination based on sexual orientation for state employees
      11. Lutheran Church of America encourages the welcoming of homosexuals as full members of their community
      12. Minneapolis, procurator for a male prostitution service charged with one year in a workhouse for exposing prostitutes to AIDS
      13. Sports Report, interview with bowler "Gutter George"
      1. This Week in Gay History, with Jeff Bixby
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, clips from a show about witch doctors in South Africa dealing with AIDS
      3. Announcement of book, "Conversations with my Elders" by Boze Hadleigh
      4. Interview with Nicholas Deutsch, director of the off-Broadway play "Jerker"
      COMMERCIAL: Zamir Furs
      5. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of the off-Broadway play "Groucho: A Life in Review"
      6. Razor Sharp gives etiquette pointers for telephone sex
      COMMERCIAL: TeleContractor phone sex hotline
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 4 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 1/16/1987], January 1987; ID: 231.0722 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0722)
      2. Short news bits
      3. Discussion of ex-gay man with AIDS who wants to be married in a Catholic church and discrimination against gay people and persons with AIDS
      4. Discussion of the "Baby M" surrogate case and its possible impact on the gay community
      5. UCLA poll finds 52% of national graduating college students support laws prohibiting homosexual behavior
      COMMERCIAL: GCN's "Year in Review" VHS tape
      6. Andy Humm on the rates of unprotected sex among teenagers
      7. News Briefs, three of anti-gay Patt Robinson's tax-exempt groups audited by IRS
      8. London, Anglican churchmen advised to work out individual issues with homosexuality before attending at the bedside of a gay person dying of AIDS
      9. Philadelphia, Colin Cook resigns from Quest ex-gay Learning center for engaging in sexual activities with students
      10. East Lansing, Michigan, agrees to strengthen anti-discrimination protection for gays and other minorities
      11. Oregon, gay inmates in prison allowed to kiss and hold hands during visits
      13. Feature story on Gay Cable Network by Japanese program "New Yorking," with behind-the-scenes footage of GCN
      2. Moments of Meditation, satirical segment with Ernest T. Lee
      3. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, announcement of "La Cage aux Folles" closing in London
      4. Interview with members of GLAAD, writers Marcia Pally and James Saslow, discussion of the media's coverage of homosexuality
      COMMERCIAL: Zamir's Furs
      5. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of off-Broadway play, "Jerker"
      COMMERCIAL: A Different Light bookstore
      6. Olivia Negron interviews Robert Drucker, banker at the Actor's Federal Credit Union
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 5 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 1/26/1987], January 1987; ID: 231.0723 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0723)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, and Evan Wolfson
      2. Discussion of gays voting for anti-gay political leaders
      3. Congress looks into banning cigarette ads, and the regulation of private decisions by government
      4. Re-opening gay bathhouses and the ethics of this
      5. Andy Humm on Catholic conservatives intervening in the youth sex education
      6. News Briefs, In Seattle, Oregon's human rights commission prohibits discrimination against persons with AIDS
      7. Connecticut's first housing complex exclusively for people with AIDS raises $30,000
      8. AZT drug available only in limited supply when it becomes available
      9. Chinese government requires foreign students to take HTLVIII virus test
      10. Austin city council passes anti-discrimination bill
      11. South Korea requires mandatory AIDS testing for all employees of service industries
      2. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, announcements
      3. Interview with Michael Petrelis a resident of the Bailey House for people with AIDS
      4. Show Bits, George Trahanis reviews Broadway play, "Stepping Out," with clips
      5. Conclusion of Michael Weyand's interview of Walter Williams, author of "The Spirit in the Flesh"
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 6 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/2/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0724 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0724)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, Kitty Cotter, and Jim Levin
      2. Short news stories
      3. Gay Catholic group petitions New York City for the right to demonstrate outside of St. Patrick's Cathedral
      4. Discussion of publicly-closeted gay politicians courting the gay vote
      5. Accurate government reporting of AIDS, and the privacy issues involved in listing AIDS on death certificates
      6. Andy Humm on Reagan's Education secretary, William Bennett, opposing AIDS Education programs in schools
      7. News Watch, Colorado lawmakers ready to approve the testing, tracing, and quarantining individuals suspected of being infected with HIV
      8. San Francisco, Chronicle discloses its policy prohibiting the listing of surviving lovers in death notices
      9. ACLU considering suing nursing homes in Illinois that refuse to accept persons with AIDS
      10. Dutch National Broadcasting Service has begun a television service for lesbians and gay men
      11. Paper finds that certain DNA viruses have the ability to activate latent AIDS viruses
      12. Senator Edward Kennedy promises adequate AIDS budget beyond Reagan's lackluster budget
      14. New segment Lavender Health, presented by the Office of Gay and Lesbian Health Concerns of the New York City Department of Health, discussion of AIDS-phobia
      15. George Trahanis interviews Jeff Goodman, Secretary of the Board of the Greater Gotham Business Council
      2. GCN Cincinnati TV episode, "Georgia Vice"
      3. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of Broadway musical "Beehive"
      4. COMMERCIAL: Night of a Thousand Gowns charity ball
      5. Olivia Negron interviews Gerard Ilaria, a volunteer social worker at New York Hospital and Columbia University Gay Health Advocacy Project
      6. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 7 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/10/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0725 (Box 46, Media ID: 231.0725)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, Joyce Hunter, and Jim Levin
      3. Updates about the March on Washington, including discussion of the demands of community on government
      COMMERCIAL: Night of a Thousand Gowns charity drag ball
      3. Criticism of GMHC's lack of an active political front, and emphasis on social service in the community
      4. Gay rights advocate and psychiatrist, Emery Hetrick's obituary
      5. News Watch, a study by the University of California, Berkeley finds that gay men who only engage in oral sex or insertive anal intercourse have a lower risk of contracting AIDS virus
      6. Philadelphia, a gay city employee charges the city with violation of its gay rights law by not allowing his lover certain rights
      7. San Francisco, openly gay Tom Nolan elected President of the San Mateo Board of Supervisors
      8. People traveling to Mexico to buy experimental AIDS treatment drugs will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law as drug smugglers
      9. Warren, Michigan, mayor bans local cable company from airing gay program "The Lambda Report" on its public access channel
      10. San Francisco, two former members of the satirical protest group, The Sisters of Perpetual Indulgence, register legally as the "official San Francisco 1987 papal welcoming committee"
      12. Lavender Health, interview with Stephen Schaefer, coordinator of the AIDS Hotline
      13. George Trahanis's closing statement
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Blue is for Boys" and interview with actor, Allen Gassman
      3. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, short news stories
      4. Judell interviews Canadian comedian, Lorne Elliott
      5. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
      6. Olivia Negron, closing statements
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 8 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/17/1987], February 1987; ID: 231.0726 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0726)
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 9 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 2/23/1987] [3]--Men and Films, Episode No. 9, February 1987; ID: 231.0727 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0727)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Darrell Yates Rist, and Tim Coglin
      3. New York Native reports that AIDS caused by syphilis spirochetes
      4. Catholic Church ejecting gay groups from their churches and forbidding them to meet or worship there
      5. Andy Humm on the marriage of an ex-gay man with AIDS in a Catholic Church
      6. News Watch, bill introduced in Maryland to remove state's sodomy laws
      7. LAMBDA legal defense hires a third attorney to full-time staff to deal exclusively with AIDS-related issues
      8. Chicago, low income gays suffer discrimination at a greater rate and degree
      9. New York, judge rules that funeral homes charging more for burial of AIDS victims are doing so illegally
      10. San Francisco, Mayor Diane Feinstein announces a reward for information leading to the arrest of the murderer of two gay men in the city's Castro district in December of 1986
      11. Arizona governor, Evan Mecham, declares that homosexuality is not a valid alternative lifestyle and therefore has no place in any argument concerning human rights
      13. Lavender Health, interview with Dr. Joan Waitkevicz of the lesbian-centered St. Marks Women's Health Collective
      1. Media Watch with Brandon Judell, interview with William H. Hoffman, playwright of "As Is," with clips of the television film
      2. Show Bits with George Trahanis, review of "Vicki's Valentine Thing," with clips
      3. Razor Sharp introduces a contest to win a date with her
    - [1]--Pride and Progress, Episode No. 10 [2]--The Right Stuff [Air Date: 3/2/1987], March 1987; ID: 231.0728 (Box 47, Media ID: 231.0728)
      1. Gay Week in Review, with Andy Humm, Eleanor Cooper, and Christopher [Wolfe]
      3. Discussion of condom distribution and the public airing of condom ads on network television, getting the gay community "condom comfortable"
      COMMERCIAL: Jose Sarria for SF AIDS Foundation
      4. Mandatory testing for HIV for those working in the public sector
      5. Andy Humm demonstrates proper condom use
      6. News Watch, Chicago Resource Center awards National Coalition of Black Lesbians and Gays $10,000 to support their magazine, "Black Out"
      7. California Fair Employment and Housing Commission unanimously rules persons with AIDS protected against discrimination on the job